BOUABDALLAOUI Yassine

PhD, M.Eng - ML and R&D Engineer

Tel: (+33)0699429946

Email: bouabdallaoui.yassin@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yassine-bouabdallaoui/

Adresse : Rouen, France.

Profile

ML and R&D Engineer with 5 years of experience using Al to drive Research and Development opportunities.

I am experienced in the combination of Mathematics, Data Science, Software development and Research. I have developed this skill set through experience in the fields of Academia, Corporate Engineering and, currently, an innovative Start-Up.

Experience

LooksGoodAl (LGAI) / ML Engineer (Mars 2022 - Present, Paris - Remote)

Using AI, LGAI develops software solutions for creating and automating PPT slides for the Consultancy business. We currently sell our products to over 30k+ users worldwide.

- Designing and developing an ML system to automate and optimise slide creation and formatting. They are currently used by **30K** + consultancy professionals ensuring 20% +productivity gain.
- Provided regular analysis to the CTO covering technological, scientific and competition updates. Using this insight, I created POC to improve our products.
- Conducted design and code reviews to ensure high performance, quality, and security standards.

Bouygues Construction (Construction 4.0) / R&D Engineer (November 2018 - November 2021, Lille)

Researcher leading the project: Artificial intelligence for Facility Management. Main tasks included:

- Developed and published an LSTM-Autoencoder model for predictive maintenance.
- Developed and published an NLP model to automate the maintenance ticketing system (save +40% on maintenance response time)
- Participated in an R&D Consortium of French leading engineering companies, to design Digital Twin solutions for O&M practitioners.

Education

Ecole Centrale De Lille /PhD in Engineering (November 2021, Lille).

Ecole Centrale De Lille and Ecole Hassaniya of Public Works / Grande Ecole Engineering Degree (2015-2018, Lille and Casablanca).

CPGE Lycée Omar Ibn Abdelaziz/ Preparatory classes: two-year undergraduate intensive courses in mathematics and physics (2013-2015, Oujda Morocco).

Technical Strengths

Computer Science: Python, Git, HuggingFace, MLFlow, Pandas, Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-learn, Numpy, AWS, NetworkX, Dataiku.

Mathematics: Statistics, Time-Series modelling, convex and non-convex optimization, graph theory. Languages: English (Fluent), French (Fluent), Arabic (Native).

Publications

- Bouabdallaoui, Y.; Lafhaj, Z.; Yim, P.; Ducoulombier, L.; Bennadji, B. Predictive Maintenance in Building Facilities: A Machine Learning-Based Approach. Sensors 2021, 21, 1044. https://doi.org/10.3390/s21041044.
- Bouabdallaoui Y, Lafhaj Z, Yim P, Ducoulombier L. Natural Language Processing Model for Managing Maintenance Requests in Buildings. 2020:1-12. https://doi:10.3390/buildings10090160.

Honors & Activities

- Co-founder of the Casablanca Science Festival in 2016 (inspired by "la fête des sciences").
- Second place in the Al Hackathon organised by the Bouygues Group in 2021.
- Member of a local football team, also a huge fan of European football especially the Premier League.